[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e8", "question": "Carlos Irwin Est\u00e9vez is best known by what stage name?", "answer": "Charlie Sheen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963e", "question": "How is film star Marion Morrison better known?", "answer": "John Wayne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3e", "question": "What teenage trauma did Ben Folds commemorate in his 1997 hit \"Brick\"?", "answer": "His girlfriend's abortion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc971ec223966ae8f8896", "question": "What alias did the infamous Keyser S\u00f6ze go by throughout most of the film \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Roger \"Verbal\" Kint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa83", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbc935f60f0007efaba0e5c", "question": "What is the name of Zorro's horse?", "answer": "Tornado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4fcfa5fdd6dd25324ea", "question": "Central African Republic shares its eastern border with which country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b6", "question": "What company produced the \"Brownie\" camera?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25737b63e5727cf5a4842", "question": "What decade saw the rapid growth in 3D puzzle popularity, largely driven by the Puzz 3D brand?", "answer": "1990s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febabf47e83c707845b20e9", "question": "What species holds the Guinness World Record for heaviest insect?", "answer": "Goliath beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f97", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecb", "question": "What French word for \"jewel\" became a common name for American movie houses?", "answer": "Bijou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ede908d98002fdd633cd", "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b481", "question": "What year did the Franco-Prussian War begin?", "answer": "1870", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339961", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Milhouse's last name?", "answer": "Van Houten", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d831709c1c34536e6ea5", "question": "What is the protective coating called that covers chicken eggs when they're hatched?", "answer": "Bloom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915a", "question": "Who is Bugs Bunny's archenemy?", "answer": "Elmer J. Fudd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a152", "question": "Whose second album was the chart-topping \"No Need to Argue\"?", "answer": "The Cranberries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03f44aa1c9af2684d79a6", "question": "Who was the mother of the Minotaur?", "answer": "Pasipha\u00eb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b37", "question": "According to a song from \"The Music Man\", how many trombones were in the big parade?", "answer": "76", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a410", "question": "Which US state is sometimes referred to as the Beaver State?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb14", "question": "How many playing pieces does each player begin with in Backgammon?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcff", "question": "What American company had a thirty-foot inflatable gorilla atop its Rhode Island offices for decades?", "answer": "Samsonite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728c856bcd28c119383288", "question": "What is the first event in a Women's Heptathalon?", "answer": "100 Metres Hurdles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7c", "question": "What Top Gun actor loses his left arm in the movies \"Total Recall\" and \"Starship Troopers\"?", "answer": "Michael Ironside", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a31", "question": "What future Broadway hit closed in Boston rather than obey a court order to cut the nudity in 1970?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895e", "question": "What was Cinderella's real name?", "answer": "Ella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f1159a72b906b34e3d01", "question": "What name is given to a cockerel that has been castrated, and often fattened, to increase the quality of its meat?", "answer": "Capon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b370ea1c3f17ccc40c8e1a", "question": "A pub that is required to sell beer primarily from a single brewery is typically referred to as what?", "answer": "Tied house", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6e", "question": "What parade first wound through New Orleans streets in 1838?", "answer": "Mardi Gras Parade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a7", "question": "What shape is produced by bees when constructing a honeycomb?", "answer": "A hexagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c515", "question": "What disease is the focus of oncology?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396be", "question": "Which Spice girl was the only one named after a spice?", "answer": "Ginger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af00", "question": "Who was the 16th president of the US?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a3", "question": "Who was made a general in 1935, when he was selected to create the Nazi Luftwaffe?", "answer": "Hermann Goering", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b436", "question": "Which Italian city was severely damaged by an earthquake in 1908?", "answer": "Messina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339483", "question": "What powers Monstropolis in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Screams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92d", "question": "What game has the winner striking the loser's wrist with two extended fingers?", "answer": "Rock, Paper, Scissors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ad", "question": "What are the six most abundant Greenhouse Gases?", "answer": "Water vapour, carbond dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, ozone and chlorofluorocarbons.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fc", "question": "What famous street follows the line of a twelve-foot stockade begun in 1653 by Peter Stuyvesant?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e80658de59ea584496feb0", "question": "The character Smike appears in which Dickens novel?", "answer": "Nicholas Nickleby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3d54ff048f679a45ab4a", "question": "What is Gregor Mendel known to be the father of?", "answer": "Genetics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01c", "question": "What U.S. President declared \"The ballot is stronger than the bullet\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ee", "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?", "answer": "Greyhound Racing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e3", "question": "What bluegrass/folk/country singer is often backed by a band called Union Station?", "answer": "Alison Krauss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f26", "question": "Radio's first spin-off, \"The Great Gildersleeve\", originated from what other comedy series?", "answer": "Fibber McGee and Molly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdff4ab668d7dfe168b5b6", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills/Drugs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b249", "question": "Who took the throne in the \"Glorious Revolution\" of 1688?", "answer": "William and Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39e", "question": "Who invented the cash register in 1879?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e89", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Griffin?", "answer": "Eagle and lion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8e", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Van Winkle?", "answer": "Vanilla Ice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a90620565ad31a57c7fb", "question": "Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?", "answer": "Jack Ruby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c53f0775fa611bce67c5", "question": "What part of a building do trusses support?", "answer": "Roof", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a2", "question": "A rabbit punch is a blow to what part of the body?", "answer": "Neck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51f", "question": "Which body joint includes the patella?", "answer": "Knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8f", "question": "Which Protestant Reformer outlawed the Feast of Saint Nicholas in 1545?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05d", "question": "Which constitutional amendment gives US citizens the right to bear arms?", "answer": "Second", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914f", "question": "Who was the Greek god of volcanoes?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078b300eee65b76b9f2664", "question": "Which U.S. president had a home called The Hermitage?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fd", "question": "What was the better known name of the old 91 meters sprint race?", "answer": "100 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31d", "question": "John Travolta, Samuel Jackson, Uma Thurman starred in which 1994 Quentin Tarantino film?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43f", "question": "What mammal's most common species is the bottlenose?", "answer": "Dolphin's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bace", "question": "What ingredient must French vanilla ice cream have in it to distinguish it from regular vanilla?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f59", "question": "What famous clipper ship took its name from Scots words for \"short shirt\" in a Robert Burns poem?", "answer": "The Cutty Sark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f11bff048f679a45aaad", "question": "Xenophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Strangers or foreigners", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951b", "question": "Who voiced Hercules in the 1997 Disney movie with the same name?", "answer": "Tate Donovan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e9", "question": "What is the only insect that can turn its head like humans?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afd", "question": "Based on total pop chart success, what woman was named \"Artist of the Decade\" for the 1990's by Billboard magazine?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69aa020565ad31a57c755", "question": "What city was the last imperial capital of Vietnam under the Nguyen dynasty?", "answer": "Hue", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c896", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc2", "question": "By tradition, what can you call yourself if you were born within the sound of London's Bow bells ringing?", "answer": "Cockney", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c357", "question": "Who is the drug morphine named after?", "answer": "Morpheus, the Greek god of dreams", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b4", "question": "Which Major League hitter drove in the most runs in a single season between 1980-89?", "answer": "Don Mattingly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a14", "question": "Where does Spanish rain fall, according to \"My Fair Lady\"?", "answer": "On the plain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a09", "question": "Who played the first \"Tool Time Girl\" on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f0d67d274615ecf514533", "question": "What U.S. President's family home was known as the \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\"?", "answer": "John Tyler", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a8", "question": "What two types of ashes are jointly called coal ash?", "answer": "Fly Ash and Bottom Ash", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b985", "question": "What name is given to the vertical bar of a window?", "answer": "Mullion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a4", "question": "What is the lowest layer of the Earth's atmosphere called?", "answer": "Troposphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25b7db63e5727cf5a4859", "question": "Who performed the singles \"All The Small Things\" and \"Adam's Song\"?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d40", "question": "What two popular TV shows are based in the town of Hooterville?", "answer": "Green Acres and Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c0", "question": "What legendary actress was nicknamed \"The Face\"?", "answer": "Greta Garbo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d5", "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what monument protruded from the rocks?", "answer": "Statue of Liberty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f74c4a9e54d890926f6ff", "question": "In June in Wyoming, it is illegal to take a picture of what?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b311", "question": "Peter the Great is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e5bffe83fe1f2a824bc4", "question": "In the Bible, Jesus referred to the disciples James and John as Sons of whom?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfc", "question": "What is the lowest ranking ace in bridge?", "answer": "Clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944c", "question": "Mel Gibson both directed and starred in which 1995 movie?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd7", "question": "What TV show did \"Empty Nest\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Golden Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3e4eff048f679a45ab59", "question": "What is a plant with no internal system of tube like structures called?", "answer": "Nonvascular Plant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "593c4bdab8198b9a2b077966", "question": "Which \"Die Hard\" film also stars Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Die Hard with a Vengence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d27", "question": "What children's books character is scared of Heffalumps and Woozles?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f46", "question": "What 1995 film was Robert Rodriguez's big-budget follow-up to the low-budget hit \"El Mariachi\"?", "answer": "Desperado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec22ac8dc25ca9e12ef629", "question": "Which French singer and actor sings the theme song to Disney's film \"The Aristocats\"?", "answer": "Maurice Chevalier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab89", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90cf5552800b05cac20f09", "question": "What US state is nicknamed \"Little Rhody\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc8", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Castaways?", "answer": "Liar Liar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a933", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Portugal?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2c", "question": "What began on the early morning of Sunday, September 2, 1666, near London Bridge?", "answer": "The Great Fire of London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a87", "question": "In \"Minority Report\", what part of Tom Cruise's anatomy does his character replace to help him avoid authorities?", "answer": "His eyes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c931", "question": "What is the common name for the sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7a", "question": "In 2008, the city of Milwaukee unveiled a statue honoring what \"Happy Days\" character?", "answer": "Fonzie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66188a5bfecdd737e083c", "question": "Whose massively popular photo led to the creation of Google Images?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23f", "question": "What year did Elton John release his fourth studio album \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf31", "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?", "answer": "Greyhound Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c020", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c79", "question": "What animal is Indiana Jones afraid of?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5623c73aa70ea0b70b28", "question": "In which state of the United States would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66161a5bfecdd737e083b", "question": "What movie holds the record for most weeks at #1 at the box office?", "answer": "E.T.: The Extraterrestrial", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bb", "question": "Which Rolling Stones hit was reputedly based on Martha Reeves and The Vandellas \"Dancing In The Street\"?", "answer": "I Can't Get No Satisfaction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40f", "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb1", "question": "What event inspired Herbert Morrison's famous quote \"Oh, the humanity!\"?", "answer": "The Hindenburg disaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa6296ce05a3942286ecc", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Frances McDormand plays the pregnant police chief of what town?", "answer": "Bernard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65c4c1f3c0ead6880d611", "question": "To what British politician was Princess Diana directly related?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20a", "question": "Who won Best Supporting Actress for her role in the 1980's film \"Melvin and Howard\"?", "answer": "Mary Steenburgen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339052", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Cry, the Beloved Country\"?", "answer": "Alan Paton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a06fcad1ec93f27df76c", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c929", "question": "What is a bactrian?", "answer": "Two-humped camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b86831d8c1817608d53e5", "question": "In which wing of the White House is the Oval Office located?", "answer": "West wing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65825ae7e414034b5aee8", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afb", "question": "Which character killed Clare Quilty?", "answer": "Humbert Humbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc09", "question": "What high civilian Indian award was Mother Teresa awarded?", "answer": "Bharat Ratna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dcf306d333868d34d6fd", "question": "Who won four gold medals in the 1936 Olympics, infuriating Adolf Hitler?", "answer": "Jessie Owens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe4", "question": "What 1997 epic was retitled \"His Powerful Device Makes Him Famous\" for Hong Kong release?", "answer": "Boogie Nights", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72b", "question": "How do Japanese children refer to Santa Claus?", "answer": "Santa no ojisan or Uncle Santa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339086", "question": "What form of verse is \"Paradise Lost\" written in?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c85dfbde8045e48466d7", "question": "What is Johannes Kepler best known for?", "answer": "Kepler's laws of planetary motion are three scientific laws describing the motion of planets around the Sun.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a94a761d1b4d384d5d66f", "question": "What is Queen Latifah's birth name?", "answer": "Dana Elaine Owens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dd5af4f3bc4a292f8620", "question": "During World War I and World War II, German submarines were called U-boats. What does \"U\" stand for?", "answer": "\"Unterseeboot\"-- It is German for undersea boat.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a8", "question": "In what US state is Dulles International Airport located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede07e6ce05a3942286db9", "question": "What's the dog's name in \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339020", "question": "Which US author penned the novels \"Of Mice and Men\" and \"East Of Eden\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a5", "question": "The 1962 movie \"Lawrence of Arabia\" was based on the real-life exploits of whom?", "answer": "T.E. Lawrence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded2caea2747c8aff16d42", "question": "What line on a weather map links all points of equal pressure?", "answer": "Isobar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2cf712596a59cbdfbd36f", "question": "Potassium Nitrate is also known as what?", "answer": "Saltpeter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a00", "question": "What 1981 thriller opens with the discovery of three faceless corpses at an amusement park in Russia?", "answer": "Gorky Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b75", "question": "In \"Napoleon Dynamite\", what type of animal is Napoleon's grandmother's pet, Tina?", "answer": "llama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339293", "question": "What 2007 film follows the crew of the Icarus II as they attempt to reignite a falling sun?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9922596a59cbdfbd3c7", "question": "Which Joseph Glidden invention put an end to open-range cattle drives?", "answer": "Barbed wire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b51", "question": "What is the better known name of musician born Reginald Kenneth Dwight?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed6", "question": "What colour is chablis?\u00a0", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a7", "question": "What two countries edge the Victoria Falls?", "answer": "Zimbabwe and Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdd0dec223966ae8f88fd", "question": "Which Yankee was nicknamed \"The Iron Horse\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdabc4e0b8cce1e6fda705d", "question": "Which ingredients are used for making \"ants on a log\"?", "answer": "Raisin, peanut butter and celery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc55", "question": "Who was the first woman to head the International Montary Fund?", "answer": "Christine Lagarde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a972461d1b4d384d5d680", "question": "What is a travelator?", "answer": "Horizontal escalator, or a moving walkway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c4", "question": "Who sang the song \"Beat It\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f84fb4e2c7fbd3896751", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \u201cBlack Velvet\u201d cocktail into a \u201cPoor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\u201d cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf4", "question": "What Japanese company was responsible for publishing the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Taito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c617", "question": "How many chromosomes are in human DNA?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008ee5cf842fa4c4ba96b6", "question": "What were \"Jelly Babies\" renamed to in 1918 to mark the end of World War I?", "answer": "Peace Babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c37e9815febcc896f9276", "question": "What is the fifth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Leo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e91065ed7247dfc0fa00315", "question": "At what point does hydrogen turn from a solid to a liquid?", "answer": "Approximately 14 K, -259\u00b0 C, or -434\u00b0 F.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67d", "question": "For what game were two jokers originally included in a standard deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Euchre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae94fc574a5ce6b56b824e", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf51f83302ff91e46492", "question": "What is the stage name of Roberta Joan Anderson?", "answer": "Joni Mitchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51717ff04d658268c92f8", "question": "What was Cleopatra's ethnicity?", "answer": "Despite being born in Egypt, Cleopatra's ancestral roots are planted in Macedonian Greece.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9930ebfabb9c85d8a970", "question": "What film starred Rosie O'Donnell, Rita Wilson and Meg Ryan?", "answer": "Sleepless in Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c669", "question": "Who developed the light bulb while working in his Menlo Park laboratory?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9bbd8364247bf200fb8a9", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the north?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b605", "question": "Which impressionist featured his wife Camille, in \"The Woman in the Green Dress\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ef", "question": "Fear of the color white is known as what?", "answer": "Leukophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bc", "question": "What is an Aasvogel?", "answer": "A vulture", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c0", "question": "In what 1959 movie do two unemployed male musicians join an all-girls band?", "answer": "Some Like it Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb1fd7e83c707845b210f", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road to eat are called what?", "answer": "A wake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a8", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Pelican State\"?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebc", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Solla Sollew\"?", "answer": "Seussical", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b313", "question": "The Suez Crisis of 1956 was precipitated by Egypt's plans to do what?", "answer": "Nationalize the Suez Canal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c42", "question": "What clarinetist was nicknamed the \"King of Swing\"?", "answer": "Benny Goodman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dd", "question": "What mythological beast has the head of a man, the body of a lion, and the tail and feet of a dragon?", "answer": "Manticore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff1423ab0ee8c595b6d39ab", "question": "What is the name of the thousand-year-old secret society depicted in \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Priory Of Sion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc3", "question": "Which country was the scene of the Mau Mau rebellion in the 1950s?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c29e4f032c0db195b483", "question": "Who served as chief minister to King Henry VIII of England from 1532 to 1540?", "answer": "Thomas Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8f", "question": "What kind of animal is pictured on the wrapper of a Klondike bar?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cc", "question": "What is the northernmost Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e96747ccba3ffe45786ee", "question": "In which European country would you find the Tokaj wine region?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad1", "question": "What name is shared by America's first Naval hero and the bass player for Led Zeppelin?", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb00665ff7d326b622a5f", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600242374be4723ccac22182", "question": "Which leading English poet of was killed in action during World War I one week before the end of the war?", "answer": "Wilfred Owen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfbdae003d27d341092bc9", "question": "In which state does the Rio Grande begin?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc0e02469bb8041d07a05c", "question": "In the health world, what does \"BMI\" stand for?", "answer": "Body Mass Index", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9f", "question": "What colour are shelled pistachio nuts?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5cbd5dad637d903c881f", "question": "What is the official State fruit of New York?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75c", "question": "What number of latitudinal parallel separates North and South Korea?", "answer": "The 38th North", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd24", "question": "What's the official title of the chief electrician on a movie set?", "answer": "Gaffer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab3320b8cce1e6fda7043", "question": "What common animal is constitutionally protected in Florida?", "answer": "Pigs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b53", "question": "Cate Blanchett received an Oscar nomination in 2008 for portraying what male musician?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f2", "question": "Who sang the title song for the 1978 suspense film \"Eyes of Laura Mars\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6b", "question": "What is Dodger Stadium also known as?", "answer": "Chavez Ravine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4db", "question": "What do you get when you mix tequila, triple sec and lime juice?", "answer": "A Margarita", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5c", "question": "What is the capital of Rwanda?", "answer": "Kigali", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76fd0eec85e375820b2f0", "question": "What's the largest freshwater lake in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1f378145fb2946670739a", "question": "What cheese is traditionally used on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaa", "question": "What is the state capital of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136fc4138175489539637c", "question": "What item gives the Green Lantern his power?", "answer": "Ring -- Turns out the key to being one of the most powerful superheroes in the DC universe is the ability to accessorize.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babe", "question": "What is the five-letter term for a rabbi who performs ritual circumcisions?", "answer": "Mohel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db9", "question": "How does the hook-handed Woody Harrelson lose his right hand in the film \"Kingpin\"?", "answer": "In a bowling ball return", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590721963745b36be73039f8", "question": "What were Frosty the Snowman\u2019s eyes made out of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b2", "question": "What color flag is the signal for surrender?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062d1ac9d816e292245c31", "question": "What landmark work came about from a friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte?", "answer": "\"The Son of Man\"\u00a0(A friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte, which was a man's face obscured by a piece of fruit.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc3906ce05a3942286f24", "question": "Lindsey Buckingham is the lead guitarist for what British-American band?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c1", "question": "Coq au vin is a dish made with which type of meat?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a0", "question": "What is the second most common element in the Sun after hydrogen?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600399bb57a0e35c43f8389f", "question": "What German artist had Emperor Rudolph II as a patron?", "answer": "Hans von Aachen\u00a0-- He was one of the leading painters of Northern Mannerism and a painter of princely and\u00a0 aristocratic portraits.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5901dc4b709c1c34536e6eb5", "question": "What does someone become after being canonized?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5d", "question": "What literary work inspired Sting's \"Moon Over Bourbon Street\" song?", "answer": "Interview with a Vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75e", "question": "Which countries border Chile?", "answer": "Peru, Bolivia and Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b981", "question": "What used to be called the apple of love or love apple ?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add8", "question": "When did the \"Eighty Years War\" end?", "answer": "1648", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b4f9e662d71a53650ff3", "question": "What did both of Edgar Allen Poe's parents do for a living?", "answer": "They were actors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd1", "question": "What is the shortest and bloodiest of Shakespeare's plays?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bf", "question": "When the Simpsons go camping, where does Maggie spend her first night?", "answer": "With bears in a cave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd62", "question": "What delicacy comes from Wagyu cattle?", "answer": "Kobe beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68a", "question": "Ranger VII was the first US spacecraft to send back pictures of what?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a551b63e1c6f9840ba318e", "question": "Which country owns the island of Corfu?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "593c4c98b8198b9a2b07796a", "question": "In which city does Spider-Man live and protect?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c688", "question": "Who took a leave of absence in the mid 1940's from his position at Cal Tech to direct the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5c", "question": "Who painted the world famous \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c34", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cf", "question": "Who directed the 2007 sci-fi movie \"Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Danny Boyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65d8f1f3c0ead6880d61d", "question": "In World War II, what type of airplane did Marine ace Pappy Boyington fly?", "answer": "F4U Corsair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe738e8eec85e375820b26a", "question": "Where is the USA's first ski town located?", "answer": "Woodstock, Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a080", "question": "What was Captain Jean Luke Picard's favorite tea in \"Star Trek: The Next Generation\"?", "answer": "Earl Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f8e7fe83fe1f2a824c30", "question": "On 1 April 1946, which disaster struck Hawaii which people initially thought was a hoax?", "answer": "Tsunami -- The disaster killed 160 people and was dubbed the April Fools Tsunami because so many thought the warnings a hoax.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f15101dd7bf43be5e804", "question": "What is the name of the gigantic silver sphere at EPCOT?", "answer": "Spaceship Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38a", "question": "What ferrous alloy has a minimum of 10 percent chromium content?", "answer": "Stainless steel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59068223ff9c0647b50a809a", "question": "Which US Senator was nominated as Hillary Clinton\u2019s vice presidential running mate?", "answer": "Tim Kaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e9", "question": "The first American blood bank was established in 1937 in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6a", "question": "What age of exploration began on October 4, 1957?", "answer": "The Space Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52f571bf59ab7d2e38114", "question": "What ingredient turns a martini into a dirty martini?", "answer": "Olive juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f86a01dd7bf43be5e842", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with an \"O\" on them minted?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd7", "question": "Which US vice president shot a Texas attorney while out hunting quail in 2006?", "answer": "Dick Cheney", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c4", "question": "Who played the role of Jenna Maroney on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Jane Krakowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a027", "question": "Which \"Family Guy\" character is employed as a pilot?", "answer": "Glenn Quagmire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ba", "question": "Which is the fourth planet from the Sun?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0db", "question": "What Tennessee university was the first college to field a men's basketball team, in 1893?", "answer": "Vanderbilt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1c", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Norma Shearer and Kirsten Dunst?", "answer": "Marie Antoinette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ea28b24f84e0b9f9ffd0", "question": "What is a figure with eight sides called?", "answer": "Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f089ff048f679a45aa9e", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea37c0ff048f679a45ab1d", "question": "What is the rarest blood type?", "answer": "AB negative", "category": "science"}]